

101, Pristine Pride Apt. 18th Main, Padmanabhanagar, Chikkalsandra, 560061, Bangalore, India

□ (+91)998-606-0477 | Inithin2889@gmail.com | Inithin2889.github.io/portfolio/ | Inithin2889 | Inithin2889 | Inithin2889 | Inithin2889

"Creating seamless user experiences."

# Summary.

Currently, Sr. Applications Developer in a company called Azket E-Intelligence have 5+ years of experience specializing in web development using Java frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, and HTML and CSS. To optimize, and a scalable code, I use clean architecture for coding. I also have experience working on the RESTful web services to provide SEO friendly URLs. Also, I code in Android in my leisure time. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

AZKET e-intelligence. Texas, USA

SR. APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER Mar. 2017 - PRESENT

- Implemented RESTful Web Services utilizing the HTTP verbs like GET, POST, PUT, DELETE for CRUD operations.
- Proficient in parsing the JSON bare bones data and embed it into a JavaScript library.
- Used Test Driven Development strategy to separate the implementation from the test code and successfully used Spring Dependency Injection.
- Acted as a Scrum Master for an Agile development team by maintaining the Releases and Sprint backlogs.
- Technologies Used: Java, JSP, Servlets, JSTL, JDBC, JavaScript, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, RESTful Web Services, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Maven Build Tool, Client-Server and MVC architectures.

### **VSM Software / Oracle Financial Services Software**

Bangalore, India

June. 2014 - Feb. 2017 **APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER** 

- · Implemented a front end screen for Flexcube. Wrote PLSQL packages for handling business logic and backend validations.
- · Maintained high level of unit test coverage through test-driven development. Implemented Test cases using JUnit and tested web services with
- Efficient use of various design patterns such as MVC Model-View-Controller, Singleton, DAO Data Access Object, DTO Data Transfer Object.
- Managed tasks within Agile framework, cleared Sprinted tasks.
- Awarded a permanent position in Oracle internally from being a contractor for good performance technically.
- Technologies Used: Java, JSP, Servlets, JSTL, JDBC, JavaScript, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, RESTful Web Services, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Maven Build Tool, Client-Server and MVC architectures.

## **Processware Systems Pvt Ltd.**

Bangalore, India Feb. 2012 - May. 2014

#### JR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Implemented overall Android application logic and consumed RESTful APIs from the app, along with a lead engineer.
- Conceptualized, designed, developed the application as per the Sprint Backlogs.
- Proficient in object-oriented design, data structures, problem solving, complexity analysis, and debugging
- Involved in the creation of Class Diagrams, analysis and design of the application.
- Extensively used JavaScript for client side validations.
- Technologies Used: Java, Android, RESTful Web Services, JSP, Servlets, JSTL, JDBC, JavaScript/jQuery, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Maven Build Tool, Client-Server and MVC architectures.

### Education.

### VTU(Visvesvaraya Technological University)

Bangalore, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

July. 2007 - July. 2011

 Lead developer and Single Point of Contact for my final year project for which I have been awarded the project completion certificate from ISRO Satellite Center.

# Achievements\_

### Android Nanodegree from Udacity, co-created by Google

Texas, USA

Apr. 2017 - Sept. 2017

ANDROID DEVELOPER

- · Developed five Android applications as part of the curriculum within 7 months of start of the course and saved 50% on the actual fees.
- · Built an Android app of my own design in two stages. In Stage 1, app was designed and planned, in Stage 2, actual app was built using my Stage 1 document as a guide.
- All Android Development has been hosted on my GitHub repository.
- · Published and updated the application on the Google play store as "Giant Bomb Games". Download the app here http://bit.ly/2j6ASYb

NITHIN PRASAD · RÉSUMÉ NOVEMBER 19, 2017